<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quickstart Guides on OrangeFS Documentation</title>
    <link>/quickstart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quickstart Guides on OrangeFS Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/quickstart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickstart Package Installation Guide</title>
      <link>/quickstart/quickstart-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/quickstart-package/</guid>
      <description>Packages for OrangeFS are available in the Fedora repositories. Packages for CentOS are available in Fedora&amp;rsquo;s EPEL (Extra Packages for Enterprise Linux) repository. The packages are available on Fedora 27 and later and CentOS 7 and later.
A number of packages are available. The OrangeFS package provides the client and the orangefs-server package provides the server. The orangefs-devel package is required to build additional programs against OrangeFS. There is also an orangefs-fuse package providing FUSE support, which is not described by this guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickstart Source Build Guide</title>
      <link>/quickstart/quickstart-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/quickstart/quickstart-build/</guid>
      <description>This topic provides an example of a complete installation of OrangeFS from source in a single procedure. It can also be used as a Quick Start reference for experienced users who wish to bypass the more detailed and segmented instructions in the earlier topics of this manual.
Notes Most of the following steps require that you have root permissions.
If your distro includes the OrangeFS kernel module, you may skip tasks related to building and installing the kernel module.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>