<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Add Server(s) on OrangeFS Documentation</title>
    <link>/add-servers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Add Server(s) on OrangeFS Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/add-servers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy OrangeFS Server Installation Directory</title>
      <link>/add-servers/copy_ofs_install_directory_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/add-servers/copy_ofs_install_directory_servers/</guid>
      <description>Begin your deployment by copying the OrangeFS installation directory from the Build system to each Server system designated in your OrangeFS solution. These are the servers already identified in the OrangeFS configuration file.    System Requirements Any system that functions as an OrangeFS server requires a supported distribution of Linux.
Note For more information on supported distributions, see Preview System Requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up Server Security</title>
      <link>/add-servers/set_up_security_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/add-servers/set_up_security_servers/</guid>
      <description>To use key-based security mode, you must copy the private keys you generated on the Build system to each of your Server systems. In future versions of OrangeFS, security will be simplified.    *Note* Neither the default nor certificate-based modes of security require any additional setup on Server systems. For these modes, see the next topic, Server Startup</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Startup</title>
      <link>/add-servers/server-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/add-servers/server-startup/</guid>
      <description>You will use the OrangeFS server daemon (pvfs2-server) on each server to initialize the storage directories and start the OrangeFS server process.    Procedure Running the server involves two tasks:
 Initializing the working directories on each server for storage space Starting the server process  The first task must be performed once on each server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Server(s) Results</title>
      <link>/add-servers/results_of_add_servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/add-servers/results_of_add_servers/</guid>
      <description>At the end of the Add Servers step, each Server system will include an OrangeFS installation directory (/opt/orangefs).
If you are using key-based security mode, each Server system will also include its own private key in /opt/orangefs/etc.
     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>