<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows Client on OrangeFS Documentation</title>
    <link>/windows-client/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows Client on OrangeFS Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/windows-client/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Windows Installation</title>
      <link>/windows-client/preparing_for_installation_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-client/preparing_for_installation_windows/</guid>
      <description>*Important* Please read this section before beginning installation of the Windows Client.
Client Requirements Operating systems:
 Windows Vista Windows 7 Windows 8 Windows Server 2008 or Windows Server 2008 R2 (all editions; Server Core installation not currently supported) Windows Server 2012 (all editions; Server Core installation not currently supported)   Hardware:
 30MB disk space Other requirements dependent on usage; minimum requirements very low   Other:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to Expect</title>
      <link>/windows-client/what_to_expect_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-client/what_to_expect_windows/</guid>
      <description>When you complete the Enterprise installation process, if you have provided all the necessary inputs, the last panel in the installer offers the option to start the client. If you select this option, your system mounts the OrangeFS server you specified, and the Windows Client starts. If you are not ready to start the client, you can do it manually later.
The installation program creates two new directories on your Windows system:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing the Software</title>
      <link>/windows-client/running_the_installation_program_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-client/running_the_installation_program_windows/</guid>
      <description>To install the OrangeFS Windows Client, you need the self-extracting installation program. Two versions are available, depending on your system’s processor type (32-bit or 64-bit).
Download and run orangefs-client-version-win32.exe or orangefs-client-version-win64.exe
where&amp;hellip;
version = version number of the executable
Example: orangefs-client-2.8.5.3-win64.exe
Notes OS. It is best to run the installer as an administrative user (Administrator, for example).
After running the executable, follow these steps:
 When the installation program&amp;rsquo;s Welcome dialog displays, click Next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manual Installation</title>
      <link>/windows-client/manual_installation_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-client/manual_installation_windows/</guid>
      <description>Important The Client connects to a running OrangeFS server. If you have not yet installed the OrangeFS server components, consult the documentation and install the server before installing the Windows Client.
Follow the instructions below to install the OrangeFS Windows Client:
Download the ZIP file associated with your system type (64- or 32-bit):
 For 64-bit systems, download orangefs-windows-client-version#-win64.zip. For 32-bit systems, download orangefs-windows-client-version#-win32.zip.
where&amp;hellip;
version# is the OrangeFS version, for example, 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uninstalling the Windows client</title>
      <link>/windows-client/uninstalling_the_client_windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-client/uninstalling_the_client_windows/</guid>
      <description>Uninstalling the Enterprise Installation To uninstall the Windows client, follow these steps:
 From the Windows Start Menu, select Control Panel, then Programs and Features. Locate and select the OrangeFS Client item, and click the Uninstall button above. Follow the uninstaller steps to remove the Client. Remove configuration files under C:\OrangeFS\Client (by default) and the C:\OrangeFS\Client directories.  Uninstalling a Manual Installation Follow the instructions below to uninstall the OrangeFS Windows Client:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Client</title>
      <link>/windows-client/winclient_use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-client/winclient_use/</guid>
      <description>Information in this topic includes:
 Interfacing with OrangeFS Running the Client Understanding Security Getting/Generating New User-Mapping Certificates  Interfacing with OrangeFS When the Windows Client is running on your computer, the OrangeFS file system appears as a removable drive at the drive letter (E:-Z:). This drive letter, specified during installation, is a setting in the configuration file that can be changed. For more information, see Client Administration.
You can interact with files and directories in the file system like local files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Client Administration</title>
      <link>/windows-client/winclient_admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-client/winclient_admin/</guid>
      <description>Information in this topic includes:
 Configuration Configuring the Client Security Mode User Mapping Installing and Using Globus Toolkit (certificates only) Troubleshooting Source Code  Configuration Two configuration files exist for the OrangeFS Client:
 orangefstab orangefs.cfg   Both text files are located in the installation directory (C:\OrangeFS\Client) by default and can be edited.
The orangefstab file contains only one line entry, which is the URI address of the OrangeFS server to be mounted for Windows Client access.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>